<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<data wiki-url="http://simile.mit.edu/shelf/" wiki-section="Simile Jewish Timeline">
  <event start='3630 BC' title="First cultivation of silk">
    Legend gives credit for developing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silk#China">silk</a> to a Chinese empress, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leizu">Leizu</a> (Hsi-Ling-Shih, Lei-Tzu).
  </event>
  <event start='2070 BC' end='1600 BC' isDuration="true" title="Xia dynasty">
    The Xia Dynasty is the first dynasty in China to be described in ancient historical chronicles such as Bamboo Annals, Classic of History and Records of the Grand Historian. The dynasty was established by the legendary Yu the Great after Shun, the last of the Five Emperors gave his throne to him.
  </event>
  <event start='2000 BC' title="Bronze working begins in China">
    The earliest bronze artifacts have been found in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Majiayao_culture">Majiayao</a> culture site (between 3100 and 2700 BC),[19][20] and from then on, the society gradually grew into the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bronze_Age#China">Bronze Age</a>.
  </event>
  <event start='1650 BC' end='1050 BC' isDuration="true" title="Shang dynasty">
    The Shang Dynasty ruled in the Yellow River valley in the second millennium BC. The classic account of the Shang comes from texts such as the Classic of History, Bamboo Annals and Records of the Grand Historian.
  </event>
  <event start='1200 BC' title="Writing first used in China">
    The earliest surviving examples of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writing#China">writing in China</a> are inscriptions on so-called "oracle bones", tortoise plastrons and ox scapulae used for divination.
  </event>
  <event start='1050 BC' end='221 BC' isDuration="true" title="Zhou dynasty">
    Although the Zhou Dynasty lasted longer than any other dynasty in Chinese history, the actual political and military control of China by the Ji family lasted only until 771 BC, a period known as the Western Zhou.
  </event>
  <event start='976 BC' end='922 BC' isDuration="true" title="Reign of King Mu Wang, fifth Zhou king">
    During this reign the dynasty reaches the peak of its power and territorial control.
  </event>
  <event start='771 BC' title="End of Western Zhou dynasty">
    The capital Hao is sacked. Zhou rule continues from a new capital to the east.
  </event>
  <event start='770 BC' end='476 BC' isDuration="true" title="Spring and Autumn Period">
    Central control under the Eastern Zhou is weak and local rulers emerge.
  </event>
  <event start='750 BC' title="First metal coins are used in China">
    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_coins">Chinese coins</a> were produced continuously for around 2,500 years by casting in moulds, rather than being struck with dies as with most western coins.
  </event>
  <event start='604 BC' end='531 BC' isDuration="true" title="Laozi">
    Laozi was a philosopher of ancient China, best known as the author of the Tao Te Ching. His association with the Tào Té Chīng has led him to be traditionally considered the founder of philosophical Taoism.
  </event>
  <event start='552 BC' end='479 BC' isDuration="true" title="Confucius">
    Confucius was a Chinese teacher, editor, politician, and philosopher of the Spring and Autumn Period of Chinese history. The philosophy of Confucius emphasized personal and governmental morality, correctness of social relationships, justice and sincerity.
  </event>
  <event start='400 BC' title="Crossbow is invented in China">
    
  </event>
  <event start='475 BC' end='221 BC' isDuration="true" title="Warring States Period">
    
  </event>
  <event start='400 BC' title="First use of the cavalry in China">
    
  </event>
  <event start='400 BC' title="Compass is invented in China">
    
  </event>
  <event start='221 BC' end='207 BC' isDuration="true" title="Qin dynasty">
    
  </event>
  <event start='221 BC' end='210 BC' isDuration="true" title="Initial Construction of the Great Wall">
    
  </event>
  <event start='206 BC' end='200' isDuration="true" title="Han dynasty">
    
  </event>
  <event start='141 BC' end='87 BC' isDuration="true" title="Reign of Han Emperor Wu">
    Wu was considered one of the greatest emperors in Chinese history as the Chinese empire reaches its greatest extent.
  </event>
  <event start='400 BC' title="Records of the Great Historian">
    Sima Qian completed the first systematic history of China from c. 2600 BC until his own times. 
  </event>
  <event start='1' end='100' isDuration="true" title="Buddhism introduced into China from India">
    
  </event>
</data>